E35 ESE 500 	Independent Study	Opportunities to acquire experience outside the classroom setting and to work closely with individual members of the faculty. A final report must be submitted to the department. Prerequisite: Students must have the ESE Research/Independent Study Registration Form (PDF) approved by the department.	Credit variable, maximum 3 units.
E35 ESE 501	 Mathematics of Modern Engineering I	Matrix algebra: systems of linear equations, vector spaces, linear independence and orthogonality in vector spaces, eigenvectors and eigenvalues; vector calculus: gradient, divergence, curl, line and surface integrals, theorems of Green, Stokes, and Gauss; Elements of Fourier analysis and its applications to solving some classical partial differential equations, heat, wave, and Laplace equation. Prerequisites: ESE 318 and ESE 319 or equivalent or consent of instructor. This course will not count toward the ESE doctoral program.	Credit 3 units. EN: TU
E35 ESE 502 	Mathematics of Modern Engineering II	Fourier series and Fourier integral transforms and their applications to solving some partial differential equations, heat and wave equations; complex analysis and its applications to solving real-valued problems: analytic functions and their role, Laurent series representation, complex-valued line integrals and their evaluation including the residual integration theory, conformal mappings and their applications. Prerequisites: ESE 318 and ESE 319 or ESE 317 or equivalent, or consent of instructor. This course will not count toward the ESE doctoral program.	Credit 3 units. EN: TU
E35 ESE 512 	Advanced Numerical Analysis	Special topics chosen from numerical solution of partial differential equations, uniform and least-squares approximation spline approximation, Galerkin methods and finite element approximation, functional analysis applied to numerical mathematics, and other topics of interest. Prerequisite: ESE 511 or consent of instructor.	Credit 3 units. EN: TU
E35 ESE 513 	Convex Optimization and Duality Theory	Graduate introduction to convex optimization with emphasis on convex analysis and duality theory. Topics include: convex sets, convex functions, convex cones, convex conjugates, Fenchel-Moreau theorem, convex duality and biconjugation, directional derivatives, subgradients and subdifferentials, optimality conditions, ordered vector spaces, Hahn-Banach theorem, extension and separation theorems, minimax theorems, and vector and set optimization. Prerequisites: ESE 415, Math 4111.	Credit 3 units.
E35 ESE 514 	Calculus of Variations	Introduction to the theory and applications of the calculus of variations. Theory of functionals; variational problems for an unknown function; Euler's equation; variable end-point problems; variational problems with subsidiary conditions; sufficient conditions for extrema: applications to optimum control and/or to other fields. A term project is required. Prerequisites: ESE 318 and 319 or ESE 317 or equivalent.	Credit 3 units.
E35 ESE 516 	Optimization in Function Space	Linear vector spaces, normed linear spaces, Lebesque integrals, the Lp spaces, linear operators, dual space, Hilbert spaces. Projection theorem, Hahn-Banach theorem. Hyperplanes and convex sets, Gateaux and Frächet differentials, unconstrained minima, adjoint operators, inverse function theorem. Constrained minima, equality constraints, Lagrange multipliers, calculus of variations, Euler-Lagrange equations, positive cones, inequality constraints. Kuhn-Tucker theorem, optimal control theory, Pontryagin's maximum principle, successive approximation methods, Newton's methods, steepest descent methods, primal-dual methods, penalty function methods, multiplier methods. Prerequisite: Math 4111.	Credit 3 units.
E35 ESE 517	 Partial Differential Equations	Linear and nonlinear first order equations. Characteristics. Classification of equations. Theory of the potential linear and nonlinear diffusion theory. Linear and nonlinear wave equations. Initial and boundary value problems. Transform methods. Integral equations in boundary value problems. Prerequisites: ESE 318 and 319 or equivalent or consent of instructor.	Credit 3 units. EN: TU
E35 ESE 518 	Optimization Methods in Control	The course is divided in two parts: convex optimization and optimal control. In the first part we cover applications of Linear Matrix Inequalities and Semi-Definite Programming to control and estimation problems. We also cover Multiparametric Linear Programming and its application to the Model Predictive Control and Estimation of linear systems. In the second part we cover numerical methods to solve optimal control and estimation problems. We cover techniques to discretize optimal control problems, numerical methods to solve them, and their optimality conditions. We apply these results to the Model Predictive Control and Estimation of nonlinear systems. Prerequisites: ESE 551, and ESE 415 or equivalent.	Credit 3 units. EN: TU
E35 ESE 519 	Convex Optimization	Concentrates on recognizing and solving convex optimization problems that arise in applications. Convex sets, functions, and optimization problems. Basics of convex analysis. Least-squares, linear and quadratic programs, semidefinite programming, minimax, extremal volume, and other problems. Optimality conditions, duality theory, theorems of alternative, and applications. Interior-point methods. Applications to signal processing, statistics and machine learning, control and mechanical engineering, digital and analog circuit design, and finance. Prerequisites: Math 309 and ESE 415.	Credit 3 units.
E35 ESE 520	 Probability and Stochastic Processes	Review of probability theory; models for random signals and noise; calculus of random processes; noise in linear and nonlinear systems; representation of random signals by sampling and orthonormal expansions. Poisson, Gaussian and Markov processes as models for engineering problems. Prerequisite: ESE 326.	Credit 3 units. EN: TU
E35 ESE 521	 Random Variables and Stochastic Processes I	Mathematical foundations of probability theory, including constructions of measures, Lebesque-measure, Lebesque-integral, Banach space property of Lp, basic Hilbert-space theory, conditional expectation. Kolmogorov's theorems on existence and sample-path continuity of stochastic processes. An in-depth look at the Wiener process. Filtrations and stopping times. Markov processes and diffusions, including semigroup properties and the Kolmogorov forward and backward equations. Prerequisites: ESE 520 or equivalent, Math 411.	Credit 3 units.
E35 ESE 523	 Information Theory	Discrete source and channel model, definition of information rate and channel capacity, coding theorems for sources and channels, encoding and decoding of data for transmission over noisy channels. Corequisite: ESE 520.	Credit 3 units. EN: TU
E35 ESE 524 	Detection and Estimation Theory	Study of detection and estimation of signals in noise. Linear algebra, vector spaces, independence, projections. Data independence, factorization theorem and sufficient statistics. Neyman-Pearson and Bayes detection. Least squares, maximum-likelihood and maximum a posteriori estimation of signal parameters. Conjugate priors, recursive estimation, Wiener and Kalman filters. Prerequisite: ESE 520.	Credit 3 units. EN: TU
E35 ESE 529	 Special Topics in Information Theory and Applied Probability	Credit 3 units.
E35 ESE 531 	Nano and Micro Photonics	This course focuses on fundamental theory, design, and applications of photonic materials and micro/nano photonic devices. It includes review and discussion of light-matter interactions in nano and micro scales, propagation of light in waveguides, nonlinear optical effect and optical properties of nano/micro structures, the device principles of waveguides, filters, photodetectors, modulators and lasers. Prerequisite: ESE 330.	Credit 3 units. EN: TU
E35 ESE 532 	Introduction to Nano-Photonic Devices	Introduction to photon transport in nano-photonic devices. This course focuses on the following topics: light and photons, statistical properties of photon sources, temporal and spatial correlations, light-matter interactions, optical nonlinearity, atoms and quantum dots, single- and two-photon devices, optical devices, and applications of nano-photonic devices in quantum and classical computing and communication. Prerequisites: ESE 330 and Physics 217, or permission of instructor.	Credit 3 units. EN: TU
E35 ESE 534 	Special Topics in Advanced Electrodynamics	This course covers advanced topics in electrodynamics. Topics include electromagnetic wave propagation (in free space, confined waveguides, or along engineered surfaces); electromagnetic wave scattering (off nano-particles or molecules); electromagnetic wave generation and detection (antenna and nano-antenna); inverse scattering problems; and numerical and approximate methods. Prerequisites: ESE 330, or Physics 421 and Physics 422.	Credit 3 units. EN: TU
E35 ESE 536 	Introduction to Quantum Optics	This course covers the following topics: quantum mechanics for quantum optics, radiative transitions in atoms, lasers, photon statistics (photon counting, Sub-/Super-Poissionian photon statistics, bunching, anti-bunching, theory of photodetection, shot noise), entanglement, squeezed light, atom-photon interactions, cold atoms, atoms in cavities. If time permits, the following topics are selectively covered: quantum computing, quantum cryptography, and teleportation. Prerequisites: ESE 330 and Physics 217 or Physics 421.	Credit 3 units. EN: TU
E35 ESE 538 	Advanced Electromagnetic Engineering	The course builds on undergraduate electromagnetics to systematically develop advanced concepts in electromagnetic theory for engineering applications. The following topics are covered: Maxwell's equations; fields and waves in materials; electromagnetic potentials and topics for circuits and systems; transmission-line essentials for digital electronics and for communications; guided wave principles for electronics and optoelectronics; principles of radiation and antennas; and numerical methods for computational electromagnetics.	Credit 3 units.
E35 ESE 543 	Control Systems Design by State Space Methods	Advanced design and analysis of control systems by state-space methods: classical control review, Laplace transforms, review of linear algebra (vector space, change of basis, diagonal and Jordan forms), linear dynamic systems (modes, stability, controllability, state feedback, observability, observers, canonical forms, output feedback, separation principle and decoupling), nonlinear dynamic systems (stability, Lyapunov methods). Frequency domain analysis of multivariable control systems. State space control system design methods: state feedback, observer feedback, pole placement, linear optimal control. Design exercises with CAD (computer-aided design) packages for engineering problems. Prerequisite: ESE 351 and ESE 441, or permission of instructor.	Credit 3 units. EN: TU
E35 ESE 544 	Optimization and Optimal Control	Constrained and unconstrained optimization theory. Continuous time as well as discrete-time optimal control theory. Time-optimal control, bang-bang controls and the structure of the reachable set for linear problems. Dynamic programming, the Pontryagin maximum principle, the Hamiltonian-Jacobi-Bellman equation and the Riccati partial differential equation. Existence of classical and viscosity solutions. Application to time optimal control, regulator problems, calculus of variations, optimal filtering and specific problems of engineering interest. Prerequisites: ESE 551, ESE 552.	Credit 3 units. EN: TU
E35 ESE 545 	Stochastic Control	Introduction to the theory of stochastic differential equations based on Wiener processes and Poisson counters, and an introduction to random fields. The formulation and solution of problems in nonlinear estimation theory. The Kalman-Bucy filter and nonlinear analogues. Identification theory. Adaptive systems. Applications. Prerequisites: ESE 520 and ESE 551.	Credit 3 units. EN: TU
E35 ESE 546 	Dynamics & Control in Neuroscience & Brain Medicine	This course provides an introduction to systems engineering approaches to modeling, analysis and control of neuronal dynamics at multiple scales. A central motivation is the manipulation of neuronal activity for both scientific and medical applications using emerging neurotechnology and pharmacology. Emphasis is placed on dynamical systems and control theory, including bifurcation and stability analysis of single neuron models and population mean-field models. Synchronization properties of neuronal networks are covered and methods for control of neuronal activity in both oscillatory and non-oscillatory dynamical regimes are developed. Statistical models for neuronal activity are also discussed. An overview of signal processing and data analysis methods for neuronal recording modalities is provided, toward the development of closed-loop neuronal control paradigms. The final evaluation is based on a project or research survey. Prerequisite(s): ESE 553 (or equivalent); ESE 520 (or equivalent); ESE 351 (or equivalent).	Credit 3 units. EN: TU
E35 ESE 547 	Robust and Adaptive Control	Graduate-level control system design methods for multi-input multi-output systems. Linear optimal-based methods in robust control, nonlinear model reference adaptive control. These design methods are currently used in most industry control system design problems. These methods are designed, analyzed and simulated using MATLAB. Linear control theory (review), robustness theory (Mu Analysis), optimal control and the robust servomechanism, H-infinity optimal control, robust output feedback controls, Kalman filter theory and design, linear quadratic gaussian with loop transfer recovery, the Loop Transfer Recovery method of Lavretsky, Mu synthesis, Lyapunov theory (review), LaSalle extensions, Barbalat's Lemma, model reference adaptive control, artificial neural networks, online parameter estimation, convergence and persistence of excitation. Prerequisite: ESE 543 or ESE 551 or equivalent.	Credit 3 units. EN: TU
E35 ESE 549 	Special Topics in Control	Credit 3 units.
E35 ESE 551 	Linear Dynamic Systems I	Input-output and state-space description of linear dynamic systems. Solution of the state equations and the transition matrix. Controllability, observability, realizations, pole-assignment, observers and decoupling of linear dynamic systems. Prerequisite: ESE 351.	Credit 3 units. EN: TU
E35 ESE 552 	Linear Dynamic Systems II	Least squares optimization problems. Riccati equation, terminal regulator and steady-state regulator. Introduction to filtering and stochastic control. Advanced theory of linear dynamic systems. Geometric approach to the structural synthesis of linear multivariable control systems. Disturbance decoupling, system invertibility and decoupling, extended decoupling and the internal model principle. Prerequisite: ESE 551.	Credit 3 units. EN: TU
E35 ESE 553 	Nonlinear Dynamic Systems	State space and functional analysis approaches to nonlinear systems. Questions of existence, uniqueness and stability; Lyapunov and frequency-domain criteria; w-limits and invariance, center manifold theory and applications to stability, steady-state response and singular perturbations. Poincare-Bendixson theory, the van der Pol oscillator, and the Hopf Bifurcation theorem. Prerequisite: ESE 551.	Credit 3 units. EN: TU
E35 ESE 554 	Advanced Nonlinear Dynamic Systems	Differentiable manifolds, vector fields, distributions on a manifold, Frobenius' theorem, Lie algebras. Controllability, observability of nonlinear systems, examined from the viewpoint of differential geometry. Transformation to normal forms. Exact linearization via feedback. Zero dynamics and related properties. Noninteracting control and disturbance decoupling. Controlled invariant distributions. Noninteracting control with internal stability. Prerequisites: ESE 553 and ESE 551.	Credit 3 units.
E35 ESE 557 	Hybrid Dynamic Systems	Theory and analysis of hybrid dynamic systems, which is the class of systems whose state is composed by continuous-valued and discrete-valued variables. Discrete-event systems models and language descriptions. Models for hybrid systems. Conditions for existence and uniqueness. Stability and verification of hybrid systems. Optimal control of hybrid systems. Applications to cyber-physical systems and robotics. Prerequisite: ESE 551.	Credit 3 units. EN: TU
E35 ESE 559 	Special Topics in Systems	Credit 3 units.
E35 ESE 560 	Computer Systems Architecture I	An exploration of the central issues in computer architecture: instruction set design, addressing and register set design, control unit design, microprogramming, memory hierarchies (cache and main memories, mass storage, virtual memory), pipelining, and bus organization. The course emphasizes understanding the performance implications of design choices, using architecture modeling and evaluation using VHDL and/or instruction set simulation. Prerequisites: CSE 361S and CSE 260M.	Same as E81 CSE 560M	Credit 3 units. EN: TU
E35 ESE 561 	Computer Systems Architecture II	Advanced techniques in computer system design. Selected topics from: processor design (multithreading, VLIW, data flow, chip-multiprocessors, application specific processors, vector units, large MIMD machines), memory systems (topics in locality, prefetching, reconfigurable and special-purpose memories), system specification and validation, and interconnection networks. Prerequisites: CSE 560M or permission of instructor.	Same as E81 CSE 561M	Credit 3 units. EN: TU
E35 ESE 562 	Analog Integrated Circuits	This course focuses on fundamental and advanced topics in analog and mixed-signal VLSI techniques. The first part of the course covers graduate-level materials in the area of analog circuit synthesis and analysis. The second part of the course covers applications of the fundamental techniques for designing analog signal processors and data converters. Several practical aspects of mixed-signal design, simulation and testing are covered in this course. This is a project-oriented course, and it is expected that the students apply the concepts learned in the course to design, simulate and explore different circuit topologies. Prerequisites: CSE 260 and ESE 232.	Credit 3 units.
E35 ESE 565 	Acceleration of Algorithms in Reconfigurable Logic	Reconfigurable logic, in the form of Field-Programmable Gate Arrays (FPGAs), enables the deployment of custom hardware for individual applications. To exploit this capability, the application developer is required to specify the design at the register-transfer level. This course explores techniques for designing algorithms that are amenable to hardware acceleration as well as provides experience in actual implementation. Example applications are drawn from a variety of fields, such as networking, computational biology, etc. Prerequisites: basic digital logic (CSE 260M) and some experience with a hardware description language (e.g., VHDL or Verilog).	Same as E81 CSE 565M	Credit 3 units. EN: TU
E35 ESE 566A	Modern System-on-Chip Design	The System-on-Chip (SoCs) technology is at the core of most electronic systems: smart phones, wearable devices, autonomous robots, and cars, aerospace or medical electronics. In these SoCs, billions of transistors can be integrated on a single silicon chip, containing various components such as microprocessors, DSPs, hardware accelerators, memories, and I/O interfaces. Topics include SoC architectures, design tools and methods, as well as system-level tradeoffs between performance, power consumption, energy efficiency, reliability and programmability. Students gain an insight into the early stage of the SoC design process performing the tasks of developing functional specification, partition and map functions onto hardware and/or software, and evaluating and validating system performance. Assignments include hands-on design projects. Open to both graduate and senior undergraduate students. Prerequisite: ESE 461.	Credit 3 units. EN: TU
E35 ESE 567 	Computer Systems Analysis	A comprehensive course on performance analysis techniques. The topics include common mistakes, selection of techniques and metrics, summarizing measured data, comparing systems using random data, simple linear regression models, other regression models, experimental designs, 2**k experimental designs, factorial designs with replication, fractional factorial designs, one factor experiments, two factor full factorial design w/o replications, two factor full factorial designs with replications, general full factorial designs, introduction to queueing theory, analysis of single queues, queueing networks, operational laws, mean-value analysis, time series analysis, heavy tailed distributions, self-similar processes, long-range dependence, random number generation, analysis of simulation results, and art of data presentation. Prerequisites: CSE 131 and CSE 260M.	Same as E81 CSE 567M	Credit 3 units. EN: TU
E35 ESE 569 	Parallel Architectures and Algorithms	Several contemporary parallel computer architectures are reviewed and compared. The problems of process synchronization and load balancing in parallel systems are studied. Several selected applications problems are investigated and parallel algorithms for their solution are considered. Selected parallel algorithms are implemented in both a shared memory and distributed memory parallel programming environment. Prerequisites: graduate standing and knowledge of the C programming language.	Same as E81 CSE 569M	Credit 3 units. EN: TU
E35 ESE 570 	Coding Theory	Introduction to the algebra of finite fields. Linear block codes, cyclic codes, BCH and related codes for error detection and correction. Encoder and decoder circuits and algorithms. Spectral descriptions of codes and decoding algorithms. Code performances.	Credit 3 units. EN: TU
E35 ESE 571 	Transmission Systems and Multiplexing	Transmission and multiplexing systems are essential to providing efficient point-to-point communication over distance. This course introduces the principles underlying modern analog and digital transmission and multiplexing systems and covers a variety of system examples.	Credit 3 units. EN: TU
E35 ESE 572 	Signaling and Control in Communication Networks	The operation of modern communications networks is highly dependent on sophisticated control mechanisms that direct the flow of information through the network and oversee the allocation of resources to meet the communication demands of end users. This course covers the structure and operation of modern signaling systems and addresses the major design trade-offs that center on the competing demands of performance and service flexibility. Specific topics covered include protocols and algorithms for connection establishment and transformation, routing algorithms, overload and failure recovery and networking dimensioning. Case studies provide concrete examples and reveal the key design issues. Prerequisites: graduate standing and permission of instructor.	Credit 3 units. EN: TU
E35 ESE 575 	Fiber-Optic Communications	Introduction to optical communications via glass-fiber media. Pulse-code modulation and digital transmission methods, coding laws, receivers, bit-error rates. Types and properties of optical fibers; attenuation, dispersion, modes, numerical aperture. Light-emitting diodes and semiconductor laser sources; device structure, speed, brightness, modes, electrical properties, optical and spectral characteristics. Prerequisites: ESE 330, ESE 336.	Credit 3 units. EN: TU
E35 ESE 581 	Radar Systems	An introduction to the selection and processing of radar signals. Signal design for improving range and Doppler resolution, ambiguity functions, chirp and stepped-frequency waveforms, pulse-compression codes. Statistical models for radar data: range-spread, Doppler-spread, doubly spread reflectors. Matched-filter and estimator-correlator receivers for range and Doppler estimation. Tracking. Multiantenna radar receivers: interference rejection, adaptive canceling. Delay-Doppler radar-imaging using synthetic-aperture processing. Prerequisite: ESE 524.	Credit 3 units. EN: TU
E35 ESE 582 	Fundamentals and Applications of Modern Optical Imaging	Analysis, design and application of modern optical imaging systems with emphasis on biological imaging. First part of the course focuses on the physical principles underlying the operation of imaging systems and their mathematical models. Topics include ray optics (speed of light, refractive index, laws of reflection and refraction, plane surfaces, mirrors, lenses, aberrations), wave optics (amplitude and intensity, frequency and wavelength, superposition and interference, interferometry), Fourier optics (space-invariant linear systems, Huygens-Fresnel principle, angular spectrum, Fresnel diffraction, Fraunhofer diffraction, frequency analysis of imaging systems), and light-matter interaction (absorption, scattering, dispersion, fluorescence). Second part of the course compares modern quantitative imaging technologies including, but not limited to, digital holography, computational imaging, and super-resolution microscopy. Students evaluate and critique recent optical imaging literature. Prerequisites: ESE 318 and ESE 319 or their equivalents; ESE 330 or Physics 421 or equivalent.	Credit 3 units. EN: TU
E35 ESE 584 	Statistical Signal Processing for Sensor Arrays	Methods for signal processing and statistical inference for data acquired by an array of sensors, such as those found in radar, sonar and wireless communications systems. Multivariate statistical theory with emphasis on the complex multivariate normal distribution. Signal estimation and detection in noise with known statistics, signal estimation and detection in noise with unknown statistics, direction finding, spatial spectrum estimation, beam forming, parametric maximum-likelihood techniques. Subspace techniques, including MUSIC and ESPRIT. Performance analysis of various algorithms. Advanced topics may include structured covariance estimation, wide-band array processing, array calibration, array processing with polarization diversity, and space-time adaptive processing (STAP). Prerequisites: ESE 520, ESE 524, linear algebra, computer programming.	Credit 3 units. EN: TU
E35 ESE 588 	Quantitative Image Processing	Introduction to modeling, processing, manipulation and display of images. Application of two-dimensional linear systems to image processing. Two-dimensional sampling and transform methods. The eye and perception. Image restoration and reconstruction. Multiresolution processing, noise reduction and compression. Boundary detection and image segmentation. Case studies in image processing (examples: computer tomography and ultrasonic imaging). Prerequisites: ESE 326, ESE 482.	Credit 3 units. EN: TU
E35 ESE 589 	Biological Imaging Technology	This class develops a fundamental understanding of the physics and mathematical methods that underlie biological imaging and critically examine case studies of seminal biological imaging technology literature. The physics section examines how electromagnetic and acoustic waves interact with tissues and cells, how waves can be used to image the biological structure and function, image formation methods, and diffraction limited imaging. The math section examines image decomposition using basis functions (e.g., Fourier transforms), synthesis of measurement data, image analysis for feature extraction, reduction of multidimensional imaging datasets, multivariate regression, and statistical image analysis. Original literature on electron, confocal and two photon microscopy, ultrasound, computed tomography, functional and structural magnetic resonance imaging and other emerging imaging technology are critiqued.	Credit 3 units. EN: TU
E35 ESE 590 	Electrical & Systems Engineering Graduate Seminar	This pass/fail course is required for the MS, DSc and PhD degrees in Electrical & Systems Engineering. A passing grade is required for each semester of enrollment and is received by attendance at regularly scheduled ESE seminars. MS students must attend at least three seminars per semester. DSc and PhD students must attend at least five seminars per semester. Part-time students are exempt except during their year of residency. Any student under continuing status is also exempt. Seminars missed in a given semester may be made up during the subsequent semester.
E35 ESE 596 	Seminar in Imaging Science and Engineering	This seminar course consists of a series of tutorial lectures on Imaging Science and Engineering with emphasis on applications of imaging technology. Students are exposed to a variety of imaging applications that vary depending on the semester, but may include multispectral remote sensing, astronomical imaging, microscopic imaging, ultrasound imaging and tomographic imaging. Guest lecturers come from several parts of the university. This course is required of all students in the Imaging Science and Engineering program; the only requirement is attendance. This course is graded pass/fail. Prerequisite: admission to Imaging Science and Engineering program. Same as CSE 596 (when offered) and BME 506.	Credit 1 unit.
E35 ESE 599 	Master's Research	Prerequisite: Students must have the ESE Research/Independent Study Registration Form (PDF) approved by the department.	Credit variable, maximum 3 units.
E35 ESE 600 	Doctoral Research	Credit variable, maximum 9 units.
E35 ESE 883 	Master's Continuing Student Status		
